# **Rivaldy**

# Android Developer

(+62) 82347541594 | rivaldy494@gmail.com | https://linkedin.com/in/rivaldy-o | https://github.com/im-o | https://rivaldy.medium.com

# **Summary**

Hi, I'm Rival, an Android Developer from Indonesia (Masamba, Makassar). I'm passionate about creating mobile applications and I often share my knowledge on medium.com, where I write about exciting topics in Android Programming. Currently, I'm diving deep into Jetpack Compose, a powerful UI toolkit for building native user interfaces, and also exploring the Flutter Framework. It's an exciting journey of discovering new ways to develop mobile app experiences.

### **Experiences**

### **Mobile Engineer**

January 2022 - May 2023

# WorkLife And Beyond (PT. Kreasi Inovasi Digital)

- Work From Home (remote).
- Develop Android Apps using Java & Kotlin language, with Modularization, Dynamic features and MVVM Pattern and third libraries like Apollo Graphql, Hilt with the concept of HTTP / Networking and local database (Room).
- Develop IOS Apps using Flutter framework with use case pattern and BLoC for state management, HTTP client with dio, GetIt for Dependency Injection with concept atomic design. (migration from native android to flutter on last month 2022)
- Worked with wireframes and UI/UX references on Figma, Zeplin and Adobe XD.
- Worked with task based SCRUM Agile Schedule (Jira) and using Github for collaboration.

### **Digital Talent Scholarship 2022**

November - December 2022

### Kominfo support by Dicoding

- Course name "Belajar Fundamental Aplikasi Android"
- Learn intermediate-level Android topics such as advanced UI, animation, localization & accessibility, services, media handling, geolocation, advanced testing, advanced database management, Firebase integration, and exam submission.
- Check out my submission at: <a href="https://github.com/im-o/dicoding-android-intermediate">https://github.com/im-o/dicoding-android-intermediate</a>

#### **Compose Learning Champion 2022**

July - September 2022

### **Dicoding**

- Course name "Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Android dengan Jetpack Compose"
- Learn Jetpack Compose for layouting, state management, lazy layout to display dynamic data, navigation, interoperability, and UI testing.
- Check out my submission at: <a href="https://github.com/im-o/dicoding-jetpack-compose-jetshopee">https://github.com/im-o/dicoding-jetpack-compose-jetshopee</a>

# IDCamp 2022 - Multi-Platform App Developer

November 2022

### **Indosat Ooredoo support by Dicoding**

 Learn Flutter Beginner from dicoding (Due to work commitments, I only took the course a few days before it closed, so I didn't get the opportunity to receive further scholarships).
 My submission: <a href="https://github.com/im-o/dicoding-flutter-beginner">https://github.com/im-o/dicoding-flutter-beginner</a>

## Flutter Engineer (Internship)

January - July 2022

### **KodingWorks**

- Work From Home (remote freelance /hour).
- Learn & Develop Android, IOS Application with Flutter Framework (state management with BLoC, Firebase, HTTP client with dio, etc.
- Worked with wireframes and UI/UX references on Figma).
- Using Gitlab for collaboration.
- Sample app:
  - https://github.com/im-o/simple-app-flutter-firebase
  - https://github.com/im-o/flutter-app-themoviedb

# Android Developer (Freelance)

June 2021 - January 2022

#### PT. Carakde Solusi Informatika

• Maintenance App Sales Force Automation (SFA)

# Baparekraf Developer Day 2021

May 2021

# Baparekraf support by Dicoding

- Course name "Belajar Android Jetpack Pro".
- I am learning about Android Jetpack, such as ViewModel, LiveData, Room, and Paging, to build applications using the Android Architecture Component.
- My project on <a href="https://github.com/im-o/dicoding-android-jetpack">https://github.com/im-o/dicoding-android-jetpack</a>

### **Android Developer**

April 2021 - January 2022

#### **Freelance Project**

- Build Android App about "Electronic Components"
- Build Android App about "MyApoteker"
- Build POS BUMDes Berdaya Bira Sulawesi-selatan. https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.imo.pos.bira

## **Android Developer**

Nov. 2020 - Nov. 2021

#### CV. Booble Mitra Kreatif

- Fixed bugs and added features from old Android POS apps.
- Build a new POS app as the main product https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.booble.boobleapp.id
- Build app for Millennial Property (Property Management Company) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.booble.id.millpro
- Collaboration with freelance programmers with Git to build Android Apps.
- Handle google play console booble.id

#### **Internship Android Developer**

August - October 2020

# PT Carakde Solusi Informatika

Joined to Carakde Internship Program, as an android developer and learn about:

- MVVM Architecture.
- Fetching data from API and Local Storage (using kotlin coroutines, retrofit, room library, etc)
- API Error Handling and Network Exception
- Contributed to building the Walet.VIP application (refactor code from MVP Architecture to Pattern MVVM Architecture) and working with UI/UX Designer and Backend Developers in rebuilding this application.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=vip.walet.carakde

#### Web applications for covid-19 information

April 2020

#### BersamaKami & Private Project

Build a web project applications covid-19 information for BersamaKami and private project for city of Palu using a Laravel Framework with CRUD features, Leaflet and retrieve data from global API covid-19. <a href="http://covid-19.bersamakami.com/">http://covid-19.bersamakami.com/</a>

# Indosat Ooredoo Digital Camp (IDCamp)

Nov. 2018 - Jan. 2019

## **Indosat Ooredoo & Dicoding**

As a student, I joined the Online Training program by Indosat Ooredoo, which was supported by Dicoding, a Google Authorized Training Partner. During the training, I focused on learning KADE (Kotlin Android Developer Expert). You can find my Dicoding academy profile at: <a href="https://www.dicoding.com/users/rivaldy">https://www.dicoding.com/users/rivaldy</a> o

# **Polinema Mobile Apps Competition**

August – September 2019

#### Department of Information Technology, State Polytechnic of Malang

Join as a participant Challenge Polinema Mobile Apps Competition 2019, and create mobile app Aplikasi Informasi Objek Wisata Enrekang". PAC is a competition place for young developers who want to be creative in the field of making Mobile Applications. demo & video: <a href="http://bit.ly/demo-app-imstimed">http://bit.ly/demo-app-imstimed</a>

# Junior Mobile Programmer

July - October 2019

#### **Digital Talent Scholarship - Kominfo**

I joined as a student in the Digital Talent Scholarship program by KOMINFO, where I attended offline classes. Additionally, I participated in the VSGA (Vocational School Graduate Academy) and joined the Junior Mobile Programmer program at Politeknik Negeri Ujung Pandang (PNUP). As part of my journey, I successfully completed the certification exam - SKKNI conducted by LSP (Lembaga Sertifikasi Kompetensi/Certification Competency Institute).

# Google Developers Kejar (GDK)

June - October 2019

### Google Developers & Dicoding

I participated as a student (Online class) in the Google Developer Kejar 2019 program, organized by Google Developers and Dicoding as their Training Partner. During the program, I focused on learning "Belajar Fundamental Aplikasi Android (Java)" to enhance my skills in Android development.

# **GO-Academy**

Join to apply for GO-JEK Upscale 2.0 by GO-Academy, a program designed for Indonesian tech students, graduates, and young professionals. Participants will have the opportunity to learn about Machine Learning, Data Modeling, and Data Science. Unfortunately, I was not selected among the 22 applicants. Here is the result of my logic test (GitHub repository): <a href="https://github.com/im-o/go-jek-upscale">https://github.com/im-o/go-jek-upscale</a>

# BEKRAF Scholarship (Developer Day 2018 - Makassar)

Nov. - December 2018

Badan Ekonomi Kreatif (BEKRAF) & Dicoding

Badan Ekonomi Kreatif (BEKRAF) provides scholarships for the Dicoding Academy class to Learn to Make Android Applications for Beginners. Course name "Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Android untuk Pemula (Java)"

# **Education**

### **Bachelor's Degree of Computer Science/Informatics**

2015 - 2020

STIMED Nusa Palapa Makassar (College of Informatics and Multimedia Nusa Palapa Makassar)

In my final project, I developed:

- An application for the city of Makassar.
- Specifically, a laundry service app similar to a marketplace app.
- The app is named "MAUDRY."
- Utilized services such as:
  - o Google Maps
  - Mapbox
  - o Firebase (FCM, Realtime Database, Cloud Storage, Authentication, etc.).